So you may remember eons ago when we were building our data set.
아주 오래 전에 데이터 세트를 만들던 때를 기억하실 거예요
At the end of that, we uploaded our data to Huggingface.
데이터를 허깅페이스에 업로드 했어요
Since that point, we since we also produced pickle files, we've been loading in the data from pickle
그 시점부터, 우린 피클 파일도 제작한 이후로 그 시점부터 피클 파일의 데이터를
files from that point onwards.
로드하고 있어요
But now that we're in Google Colab, it's easiest for us to collect that data back from the Huggingface
하지만 구글 Colab에 있으니 H깅페이스 허브에서 데이터를
hub again, which is a very typical task in this kind of, uh, process of building your own model.
수집하는 게 가장 쉽죠 자신만의 모델을 만드는 이런 과정의 아주 전형적인 작업이에요
So here I go.
그럼 시작할게요
I load the dataset using, uh, hugging face load data set method, passing in the data set name, and
데이터셋을 로드합니다 얼굴 로드 데이터셋 메서드를 끌어안고 데이터셋 이름을 전달합니다.
then I break it up into a train and a test and the data set name I set in the constants at the top.
그리고 그것을 기차와 테스트, 데이터셋 이름을 상수에 나눠 놓죠.
Once I've done that, we can take a look at the first training data point.
그 후에 첫 번째 훈련 데이터 포인트를 볼 수 있어요
And what it looks like is it has text and a price.
텍스트와 가격이 있는 것 같아요
You may remember we set this explicitly ourselves.
우리가 명시적으로 설정한 걸 기억하실 거예요
The text is our prompt.
글이 우리의 프롬프트예요
How much does this cost to the nearest dollar followed by the description of the product followed by
가장 가까운 달러의 가격은 얼마일까요? 제품 설명과 가격은
price is dollars and then the price itself, but rounded to the nearest whole number.
달러 그다음은 가격을 가장 가까운 숫자로 반올림해 볼게요
And in the top.
그리고 위에도요
Here I say, how much does this cost?
이건 얼마냐고 물어볼게요
To the nearest dollar.
최대한 많이요
And the reason I'm doing that is I want to make the task a bit easier for the llama 3.1 model with its
이렇게 하는 이유는 비트를 좀 더 쉽게 만들기 위해서예요 80억 개의 변수가 있는
puny 8 billion parameters.
단일 모델이죠
When we were sending it to a frontier model, we didn't need to specify that because it's easily powerful
개척 모델로 보낼 때 그걸 지정할 필요가 없었어요 센트에 대한 결정을 스스로
enough to make its own decisions about cents.
내릴 만큼 강력하니까요
But in this case, we want to give our model every, every, every simplicity we can.
하지만 이 경우에는 최대한 단순하게 만들고 싶어요
Um, and since it's going to, since this will always map to one token in llama 3.1, we're making it
그리고 이건 항상 라마 3에서 토큰 하나로만 매핑되니까요 아주 쉽게 만들었어요 그냥
quite easy that all it's got to do is be able to predict that one token right there.
저기 있는 토큰 하나만 예측하면 되죠
That's going to be what it's going to try and learn how to do well.
그걸 잘 하는 방법을 배우려고 할 거예요
Um, and in this data set, we also have the real price in here too.
이 데이터 세트에는 실제 가격도 있어요
Uh, if I look at the test data and take the first point, the test data is going to look very similar
테스트 데이터를 보고 첫 번째 점을 보면 구조는 아주 비슷한데 한 가지
in structure with one tiny difference.
작은 차이가 있어요
Do you know what that difference is?
그 차이가 뭔지 아세요?
I'm sure you do.
물론 그러시겠죠
It is, of course, that there is no price provided at this point in the test data.
물론 이 시점에서 테스트 데이터에 제공된 가격은 없어요
The text is going to be the text.
텍스트는 텍스트가 될 거예요
How much is this to the nearest dollar?
이게 얼마 정도 해요?
And then we pass in this text.
이 텍스트를 전달해요
And the assignment to our model is to predict the next token.
다음 토큰을 예측하는 게 우리 모델의 임무죠
What is the probability of the next token coming after this.
다음 토큰이 나올 확률은 얼마나 될까요?
And we hope it will give a high probability to the token that matches the number that is, uh, 3.74,
3이라는 숫자와 일치하는 토큰이 나올 확률이 높기를 바라야죠 74,000달러예요 실제
uh, matching the actual price.
가격과 같네요
Uh, and so that is the assignment.
그게 이번 과제예요
And because this maps to one token, it's really the challenge is just to get good at predicting the
이것은 하나의 토큰에 대응하기 때문에 다음 토큰을 예측하는 것이 매우 어렵습니다.
next token, the single next token that represents that cost.
하나의 토큰이 비용을 나타내니까요. Get in get get it.
Uh, one other point to mention is that you may remember, we did some futzing around to make sure that
또 하나 언급할 점은 기억하실지 모르겠지만 이 텍스트가 정확히
this text always fitted into exactly 179 tokens or less.
179t less 토큰에 맞는지 확인하기 위해 우리가 좀 고생을 했었죠
Um, and because of that, we're able now to tell, uh, the I've got a constant up here that says maximum
그 덕분에 이제 알 수 있는 게 여기 연속적으로 최대 시퀀스 길이가 182이라고
sequence length is 182.
나오네요
I've added in a few tokens.
몇 가지 패를 더했어요
There it is, in fact 179.
여기 있네요, 179개
But I'm adding in a few extra spare tokens, uh, because, uh, the the tokenizer is going to add in
하지만 저는 여분의 토큰을 몇 개 추가할 겁니다 토큰라이저는 문장 토큰의 시작 부분을
a beginning of sentence token to the start of the sequence, and it may add in an end of sentence or
순서 시작 부분에 추가하고 문장 끝이나 패드 토큰을 추가할 수도
a pad token or two at the end.
있기 때문이죠
And I want to have no risk at all that we accidentally chop off the price of the most important token,
실수로 가장 중요한 토큰의 가격을 오차로 처리하는 일은 없었으면 합니다
uh, which is going to come at the end of this.
마지막에 나올 토큰이죠
So given a little bit of extra leeway, in fact, this doesn't become important until we get to training.
약간의 여유만 있다면요 사실 훈련이 시작되기 전까진 중요하지 않아요 Get in get
But I wanted to point it out now since we're looking at the data.
데이터를 보고 있으니 지금 지적하고 싶었어요
So there we go.
자, 됐어요
We've just sorry, gone too far.
미안해요, 너무 심했어요
We've just looked at this data.
방금 이 데이터를 봤어요
The next thing that we do is we pick the right quantization config.
다음으로 할 일은 올바른 퀀타이즈 구성을 고르는 거죠
I set a constant up above, uh, quant four bit.
퀀트 포 비트 이상으로 상시 유지하기로 했어요
In this case I set it to true.
이 경우엔 true로 설정했죠
Let's just go and check that we will see.
가서 확인해 보죠
There we go.
됐어요
Quant four bit is set to true.
퀀트 포 비트가 트루로 설정됐어요
And so now when I come back down again, we're going to pick the four bit quantization.
이제 다시 내려오면 for 비트 퀀타이즈를 선택할게요
And I show you here what it would look like if we picked eight bit.
8비트를 선택하면 어떻게 되는지 보여드릴게요
But we're going to pick the really minuscule four bit version.
하지만 아주 작은 4비트 버전을 고를 거예요
And then we load in the tokenizer and the model.
그리고 토큰라이저와 모델을 로드하죠
I'm not going to run this cell because I already ran it.
이 방은 안 쓸 거예요 이미 썼으니까요
You can see it's sitting in the memory here.
여기 메모리에 남아 있어요
If I run it a second time I'll run out of memory.
두 번 실행하면 메모리가 부족할 거예요
And what we do here is we load in the tokenizer.
여기서 토큰라이저를 로드할 거예요
There's a bit of stuff here that's very boilerplate that you'll see a lot.
비트 박스는 상용적인 내용으로 자주 보게 될 거예요
Um, we're telling the tokenizer that when if it ever needs to pad the end of a sequence, it should
토큰라이저에 이렇게 알려 주는 거예요 시퀀스 끝에 패드를 넣어야 할 때는
just use the end of sentence token and just have that repeatedly.
그냥 문장 끝부분을 쓰면 된다고요
And it should do that off to the right hand side.
오른쪽에 이렇게 해야 해요
This is standard stuff that will happen when we train.
훈련할 때 흔히 하는 거예요
We won't actually use it right now.
당장은 안 쓸 거예요
Um, so you don't need to worry about it.
걱정 안 하셔도 돼요
But but you'll see this all over the place.
하지만 어디서나 볼 수 있죠
It's a very standard setup, as is this line here, which you also don't need to worry about right now.
아주 표준적인 셋업이죠 여기 이 라인처럼요 이것도 지금 당장 걱정하실 필요는 없어요
What we're doing is creating a tokenizer and loading in the llama 3.1 base model.
토큰이저를 만들어 llama 3을 로드하고 있어요 기본 모델 1개요
And it's using up the 5.6GB of memory that you're expecting.
5를 다 쓰고 있어요 메모리가 6GB예요
There it is, 55.9, it seems because because I've done some, uh, inference down below.
저기 있네요, 55번 9개인 것 같아요 제가 아래에 추론을 했거든요
Uh, but yeah, it's, um, it's the, the very slimmed down four bit version of the model.
아주 날씬한 4인치 비트 모델이에요
So now this function is one that should be familiar to you because we used it recently with frontier
이 함수는 여러분께 익숙할 겁니다 최근 프론티어 모델에서
models extract price, which is going to take some text, any text and pluck out from it the price that's
가격 추출에 사용했거든요 텍스트를 추출하죠 어떤 텍스트든요 예측된 가격을 추출해요
And so if I do something like extract price, price is dollar 999, I should have this as a string perhaps.
가격을 추출하는 이런 걸 하면 가격은 $999 문자열로 이걸 넣어야겠죠
So that's not going to work very well is it.
잘 안 될 것 같아요
Price is dollar 9999 blah blah.
가격은 달러 9999 어쩌고저쩌고죠
Uh price is 999.
가격은 999예요
So cheap.
정말 싸요
Whatever.
됐어요
Uh, then hopefully what we'll see.
결과가 기대되네요
Yes.
네
Is that it's going to pluck out 99999.
99999마리를 잡아낼 거예요
But the model, we know it's going to be provided with this in the in the prompt.
모델은 프롬프트에서 제공될 거라는 걸 알죠
It's what comes next has got to have nine, nine, nine in it.
9단계가 모두 포함돼야 해요
Um, and then this here model predict.
이 모델이 예측해요
So this is the function which we're going to be using in our test harness.
이게 시험용 하네스에 사용할 함수예요
This is the function where we tell it.
우리가 그걸 알려주는 함수죠
We're going to give you a prompt.
프롬프트를 하나 드리죠
And we want to know how much does this cost.
비용은 얼마나 드는지 알고 싶어요
And so this is how we call our model in inference mode similar to what we did several weeks ago.
이건 추론 모드의 모델을 부르는 방법입니다 몇 주 전에 했던 것과 유사하죠
Uh, we take the prompt and we encode it using tokenizer dot encode.
프롬프트를 가져다가 Tokenizer.ex코드를 이용해 암호화해요
And this thing here will push it off to the GPU.
이건 GPU 쪽으로 밀어내죠
Uh, this is just, uh, something that's, uh, not super important.
이건 그냥... 별로 중요하지 않은 거예요
It stops it from printing a warning.
경고문을 인쇄하는 걸 막아주죠
So, so this doesn't actually affect anything.
그럼 아무 영향도 없군요
Uh, and then, um, yeah, to be precise, this this prevents it from trying to predict anything that's
어, 그리고, 음 정확히 말하자면, 입력 토큰 영역에서 일어나는 일을 예측하지 못하게 합니다.
happening in that input token area, which we don't want it to predict, that we want it to predict
예측하지 않고, 이후에 일어날 일을 예측하고 싶어하죠.
That's what it would do anyway.
어차피 그렇게 될 거예요
But it would give a warning if we didn't explicitly tell it this.
하지만 우리가 말하지 않았다면 경고가 나왔을 거예요
So then we say for our outputs, we're going to call our base model lemma 3.1.
결과물을 위해 기본 모델 lemma 3을 호출하죠 1번요
And we're going to call the generate method on it.
그 위에 생성 메서드를 호출할 거예요
We pass in the inputs.
입력값을 통과시키죠
We're going to say the maximum new tokens we is for.
최대 새 토큰을 위한 거라고 하죠
We could make that a much smaller number.
훨씬 적은 숫자로 만들 수 있어요
We only really need one token.
토큰 하나만 있으면 돼요
I'm giving it to to generate up to four tokens, just in case it prints another dollar sign or something
4개까지 토큰을 생성하도록 할 것입니다 달러 기호를 또 출력할 수 있으니까요
Um, uh, that we pass in the attention mask that I've just set that stops it giving a warning.
방금 설치한 주의력 마스크를 통과시키면 경고가 안 뜨죠
And this is just saying we only want back one answer.
이건 하나의 답만 원한다는 거죠
We don't want it to come back with multiple answers.
여러 가지 답이 나오면 안 돼요
And then for the reply we take that one answer, it sends us back.
그 답에 대한 답변은 그 답 하나를 취하면 다시 보내지죠
And we call tokenizer dot decode to turn that back into a string.
Tokenizer.Dcoode를 호출해 다시 문자열로 바꾸죠
And then we extract that string.
그 문자열을 추출해요
All right.
좋아요
So that's exciting.
신나네요
Let's just remind ourselves.
우리 스스로 되새겨 보죠
So if we take the zeroth, the the first test item, here it is.
0을 보면 첫 번째 테스트 항목이 여기 있네요
It's the OEM AC compressor.
OEM 에어컨 압축기예요
The actual price is $374.
실제 가격은 374달러예요
Who knew.
누가 알았겠어요
So let's have our first shot at this.
첫 번째 시도예요
So we're going to say Model.predict.
Model이라고 입력하죠 예측요
Test zero.
0번째 테스트예요
And to get the prompt out of that I just call text on that.
프롬프트를 얻기 위해 get 텍스트를 호출할게요
So are you ready.
그럼 준비되셨나요?
Here we go.
시작할게요
Llama 3.1 base model is going to try and predict the price of an OEM AC compressor with something repair
라마 3요 1번 기본 모델은 OEM AC 압축기와 수리 키트의
kit okay.
가격을 예측해 보려고 해요
And it's predicted $1,800 which is rather far off.
예상 가격은 1,800달러인데 차이가 너무 커요
So that is potentially a bad omen for how the llama 3.1 base model will work.
라마 3에 대한 나쁜 징조일 수도 있어요 기본 모델 1개면 돼요
But we might have just gotten unlucky with the first example, but that will be revealed in the next
첫 번째 예시는 운이 나빴을 뿐이지만 그건 다음 영상에서 밝혀질 거예요